export const questions = [
  {
    question: "The role of orthodontics is:",
    options: {
      a: "Treatment of dental caries",
      b: "Prevention of dental caries",
      c: "Correction of dental and skeletal anomalies in orofacial area",
    },
    correct_answer: "c",
  },
  {
    question: "Local anesthetics – Choose correct answer",
    options: {
      a: "All local anesthetics contain epinephrine",
      b: "We can divide them to ester and amide anesthetics",
      c: "Cause irreversible nerve blockade",
    },
    correct_answer: "b",
  },
  {
    question: "Predisposing factor of periodontal diseases is:",
    options: {
      a: "Drinking of water with low pH",
      b: "Eating of vegetarian food",
      c: "Poor oral hygiene",
    },
    correct_answer: "c",
  },
  {
    question: "Dental hard tissues are:",
    options: {
      a: "Enamel + Cementum + Pulp",
      b: "Enamel + Dentine + Cementum",
      c: "Enamel + Dentine + Periodontium",
    },
    correct_answer: "b",
  },
  {
    question: "Temporary (deciduous) dentition consists of:",
    options: {
      a: "2 incisors + 1 canine + 2 molars",
    },
    correct_answer: "a",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the teeth are missing in primary dentition:",
    options: {
      a: "Second molars",
      b: "Premolars",
      c: "Lateral incisors",
    },
    correct_answer: "b",
  },
  {
    question: "Average number of movements in temporomandibular joint is:",
    options: {
      a: "20-30 times a day",
      b: "2-3 million times a day",
      c: "2,000-3,000 times a day",
    },
    correct_answer: "c",
  },
  {
    question: "Most frequent type of malignant tumor in the oral cavity is:",
    options: {
      a: "Squamous cell cancer",
      b: "Osteosarcoma",
    },
    correct_answer: "a",
  },
  {
    question: "Which tissues are affected by periodontitis?",
    options: {
      a: "Hard dental tissues",
      b: "Periodontal tissues",
      c: "Temporary dentition only",
    },
    correct_answer: "b",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the longest time a tooth can be outside of the socket to make replantation successful?",
    options: {
      a: "2 hours",
      b: "2 days",
      c: "2 weeks",
    },
    correct_answer: "a",
  },
  {
    question: "Dental prosthetics deals with:",
    options: {
      a: "Treatment of periodontal diseases",
      b: "Restoration of missing teeth and dental arches",
      c: "Treatment of disorder of dental pulp",
    },
    correct_answer: "b",
  },
  {
    question: "Adding fluoride to the toothpaste helps with:",
    options: {
      a: "Teeth whitening",
      b: "Prevention of oral cancer",
      c: "Prevention of dental caries",
    },
    correct_answer: "c",
  },
  {
    question: "Treatment of oral cancer is:",
    options: {
      a: "Based on combination of surgical treatment, radiotherapy and chemotherapy",
      b: "Based on bone marrow transplantation",
      c: "Possible only in advanced stages, early stages of the disease are not treated",
    },
    correct_answer: "a",
  },
  {
    question: "How many dentitions are described in humans?",
    options: {
      a: "One in males and two in females",
      b: "Three – In early age, in middle age, and in senium",
      c: "Two – Temporary and permanent",
    },
    correct_answer: "c",
  },
  {
    question: "Which microorganism is responsible for dental caries?",
    options: {
      a: "Streptococcus mutans",
      b: "Aggregatibacter actinomycetecomitans",
      c: "Escherichia coli",
    },
    correct_answer: "a",
  },
  {
    question: "The role of a dental filling is to:",
    options: {
      a: "Restore the functional role of the tooth",
      b: "Restore only the aesthetic function",
      c: "Restore the aesthetic and functional role of the tooth",
    },
    correct_answer: "c",
  },
  {
    question: "Dental enamel:",
    options: {
      a: "Is sensitive to weather changes",
      b: "Consists predominantly of water",
      c: "Is the hardest tissue in the human body",
    },
    correct_answer: "c",
  },
  {
    question: "According to the FDI numbering system, tooth number 11 is:",
    options: {
      a: "Upper central left incisor",
      b: "Lower central right incisor",
      c: "Upper central right incisor",
    },
    correct_answer: "c",
  },
  {
    question: "Myofacial Pain Dysfunction Syndrome:",
    options: {
      a: "Is a psychological disorder involving masticatory muscles causing limitations",
      b: "Is not stress related",
      c: "Causes mucosa hyperplasia",
    },
    correct_answer: "a",
  },
  {
    question: "Name complications of radiotherapy in the orofacial region:",
    options: {
      a: "Mucositis, erosions, ulceration, xerostomia",
      b: "Bisphosphonates osteonecrosis",
    },
    correct_answer: "a",
  },
];
